

BRYAN WINDSOR

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER BRYAN@WINDSOR.STUDIO

MATCHING COMPETENCIES

COMMUNICATION

Years of experience in technical management and development, education, and foreign cultures have fostered a high level of clear verbal and written communication including technical writing.

PROBLEM SOLVING

Problem-solving is a passion of mine and something I do for fun in my free time. I love puzzles, optimization, and critical thinking and I hone these skills in coding, bouldering, language-learning, gaming, and teaching.

ACCOUNTABILITY

Following-up, taking notes, organizing, and planning are skills that I have developed over many years as a professional. I am known for taking the lead through uncertain territory, acquiring resources, and ensuring proper accounting of time, objectives, and resources.

BROAD EXPERIENCE

"People who develop broad skills tend to have a good mental model of how different layers of a system behave." – Facebook Engineering, 2010 Experiences as a client and vendor, leader and follower, freelancer and employee, have all instilled the motivation and background for understanding all aspects of a project.

WHY ME

As a software developer with experience in management and education, I have a background that is relevant to all stakeholders. Colleagues and collaborators describe me as "very involved in the projects [I work] on," and an "excellent coding collaborator." Also as "someone who truly loves to learn, and [whose] ability to quickly grasp, implement, explore and debug new technologies [is impressive]." I have lived as an expatriate for more than 6 years in 3 countries and traveled through more than 15. My primary languages are English and Chinese and I can communicate in Dutch and French as well.

CONTACT

- linkedin.com/in/bryanwindsor
- +31 6 16767007
- +1 678 500 9146
- bryan@windsor.studio

RELEVANT SKILLS

JavaScript	TypeScript	React.js	Node.js
Redux	D3.js	Vue.js	Git
Jest / Enzyme	Docker	Shell / Bash	Linux / Mac
CSS / SCSS	HTML	Firebase	Bootstrap
MongoDB	PostgreSQL	REST / JSON	Heroku
Project Mgmt.	Mandarin	Dutch	English

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II • CLOCKWORK • SEP 2019 - PRESENT

At Clockwork, my position was as part of the consultancy team. While waiting for clients, my work focused on Salesforce, React, and Vue projects.

Ecosystem Tool

The Clockwork team working with Rabobank developed a method for identifying, presenting, and tracking innovation opportunities and needed to be able to digitize and automate their methodology.

- Create basic design framework
- Provide initial backend functionality
- Build front-end application
- Visualize data using D3.js's Zoomable Sunburst graph
- Delegate development tasks
- Create development backlog and sprints with product owner

Tools & Methodologies: Agile / Scrum, CSS, Git, HTML, JavaScript / ES6, Jira, JSON, Project Management, Express, Visual Studio Code, REST, Node.js, Firebase, React.js, Redux, D3.js

Clockwork website

Clockwork needed to revamp its website, but neither the original developer nor the current designer had enough time available. My team worked together under the original developer's guidance to create new pages and functionalities.

- Convert basic Adobe XD designs into code
- Create Prismic CMS templates
- Develop Vue.js pages
- Write middleware for Prismic API data processing

Tools & Methodologies: Agile / Scrum, SCSS, Git, HTML, JavaScript / ES6, Vue.js, JSON, Visual Studio Code, Prismic

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER • FREELANCE • JAN 2019 - SEP 2019

As a freelance developer, I designed and built several different apps of interest for potential use.

The Weather App

github.com/taidaid/weatherapp

A lightweight React app for displaying the weather information via a user's location, a location's name, or coordinates. The app was designed to showcase a minimalist design with intuitive functionality and responsive styling. In addition to integrating API data, the app made use of the Chart.js library for beautiful and informative graphs.

Tools & Methodologies: CSS, Git, HTML, JavaScript, JSON, REST, React.js, Darksky API, Chart.js

Face-recognition App

github.com/taidaid/face-detection

This app was built as the final project for The Complete Web Developer 2019 course. It is a clean, smooth, and lightweight app that accepts any image URL and returns the same image with outlines around each face in the photo.

Tools & Methodologies: CSS, Git, HTML, JavaScript, JSON, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Express, REST, Clarifai API

TEACHER • VIPKID • AUG 2017 - SEP 2019

East Asia has a giant industry for teaching English to Chinese speakers. My Mandarin abilities gave me a unique position to capitalize on this demand.

- 2400+ classes
- 460 students
- 1197/1207 excellent reviews
- Coach students in pronunciation with speech therapy methods
- Guide students to proper hand-writing techniques and resources
- Educate students in grammar
- Train students' listening ability

TEACHER • HEAD START • AUG 2015 - SEP 2017

Taiwan has a large demand for native English-speaking teachers and an even higher demand for those that also speak Mandarin.

- Mentor students in English public speaking
- Coach pronunciation
- Guide projects and activities
- Determine lesson plans and learning objectives
- Administer exams

DIGITAL MARKETING DIRECTOR • NATIONAL PAIN CARE • JUN 2013 - JUN 2015

National Pain Care needed to increase its brand awareness and conversion rates.

- Develop a web presence with 1 national informational website, a regional informational site per practice (4), and a localized site per clinic (15).
- Manage radio and TV ads
- Assess budget and provide performance metrics
- Integrate Prime Suite with websites

IT OPERATIONS DIRECTOR • NATIONAL PAIN CARE • AUG 2011 - JUN 2014

National Pain Care was a healthcare management startup. After acquiring several smaller clinics, it needed to reduce redundant equipment and services while increasing its disaster recovery ability and security.

- Virtualize, centralize, and secure server environment
- Secure and standardize client environment
- Completed IT overhaul for 15 locations and 300 employees
- Implemented and supported EMR software
- Implement full-mesh WAN
- Create call centers
- Train in-house IT staff

INTERIM PRACTICE MANAGER • GEORGIA PAIN PHYSICIANS • JAN 2012 - JUN 2012

Georgia Pain Physicians, a subsidiary of National Pain Care, found itself without a practice manager for a period of 6 months.

- Oversee 4 locations' clinic operations
- Manage medical assistant and technician staff
- Handle patient disputes

- Manage partner and vendor relationships and projects
- Provide new hire training in EHR and clinic operations

EDUCATION & TRAINING

COMPLETE REACT DEVELOPER IN 2019 (W/REDUX, HOOKS, GRAPHQL)

Andrei Neagoie - In progress

THE COMPLETE JUNIOR TO SENIOR DEVELOPER ROADMAP

Andrei Neagoie - In progress

UNDERSTANDING TYPESCRIPT - 2020 EDITION

Maximilian Schwarzmuller - May 2020

BUILD DATA VISUALIZATIONS WITH D3.JS & FIREBASE

Shaun Pelling – Nov 2019

ADVANCED JAVASCRIPT CONCEPTS

Andrei Neagoie - Oct 2019

REACT, REDUX, & ENZYME - INTRODUCING APPS & TESTS

David Joseph Katz - Aug 2019

THE COMPLETE WEB DEVELOPER IN 2019

Andrei Neagoie – Aug 2019

THE REACT COURSE

Flavio Copes – Jul 2019

CERTIFIED B2 MANDARIN CHINESE

National Taiwan Normal University – Aug 2014 – Sep 2017

BBA - MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS

University of Georgia - Aug 2006 - May 2011

SPECIALIZATIONS & METHODOLOGIES

JavaScript / ES6	***	React.js	***
Redux	***	D3.js	***
HTML	***	TypeScript	***
CSS	***	REST / JSON	***
Healthcare	***	Training	***
Project Management	***	Vue.js	**
Node.js	**	Express.js	**
Firebase	**	NoSQL	**
Agile / Scrum	**	Linux	**

SQL	**	SCSS	**
Python	**	Education	**
Application / System Design	**	Heroku	*
C#	*	Unity	*

LANGUAGES

	<u>Verbal</u>	<u>Written</u>
Dutch	Basic	Basic
English	Native	Native
Mandarin	Excellent	Good
French	Basic	Basic